How could you lose sight of a bag
with four million euros, Damián?
Keila called me.
The duke's money was moving.
And the duchess
wouldn't stop whispering in my ear.
I got distracted.
Not my problem you let a woman
cloud your senses up close.
I need that money
to set my plan in action.
What is it? Another Ali Baba scheme?
Or Willy Wonka and chocolate?
- What is it?
- Call it whatever you want, but find it.
How am I supposed to do that?
How many people
were at that party? 400? 500?
That's good news.
One of them has the money.
You're not dealing with seven billion
like the police usually do.
You have a list of suspects. Get to work.
Is that what I think you're carrying?
Follow me. Make yourself comfortable.
Close the door.
You have beautiful penmanship.
And the paintings?
Stay there. Do you like art?
Let's say I'm…
an enthusiast.
Yeah. Sure.
I won't hurt you. Listen before you speak.
Lie to me again,
and I'll sew your lips shut.
Do you understand?
You befriended the duke and Genoveva
to get into their palace.
Yes or no?
- Yes.
- Yes?
To rob them?
Think carefully.
Oh my God, I was losing my mind.
You go into a bathroom with her,
then say you're moving
to the palace with the duke…
I thought, "Is this guy a gigolo?"
I thought they wanted you
to spice things up.
You don't know how happy you've made me.
A thief. You're a thief.
I mean that as a compliment.
Hold on. You just violated my privacy.
Don't go all diva on me now.
I'm in the business too. I get discretion.
And you're in luck.
I'm between crews.
You see, I don't mix personal
and professional.
You're not really in a position
to negotiate my contract.
You just disturbed all my things,
now you say you're joining my crew.
and suddenly
you're not discussing the conditions.
I'm not quite comfortable
with this Andalusian matriarchy,
so I'll step out
and come back in to start over.
You've got all the evidence on me.
And I don't even know who you are.
You can turn me in
to the police or to the duke and duchess.
You know them.
You've got me…
completely at your mercy.
So how do I know
I can trust you?
You won't.
But you'll feel it.
Damián, come. We have new info.
What info?
Here's the palace chapel,
where we lost the trail.
Built in 1825.
The family mausoleum is there.
Five generations buried inside.
And here's the interesting part.
The cardinal of Seville
is buried there too.
Octavio Hermoso de Medina.
Early 19th century. Sought the papacy.
Do I look like I care
about 19th-century cardinals?
No, right?
Take a break. I've got things to do.
I'm taking a nap.
Roi, can I use your cabin?
Sure.
Take me somewhere. Right now.
It's life or death. No time.
Who are you to chase me
all the way to Seville?
What are you? A stalker? A psychopath?
I look out the window, and there you are.
My partner could have been with me.
You don't get to barge into my life.
You're nobody.
We met once,
and you think it's Fatal Attraction.
I'm not stalking anyone.
Sorry if it looked that way.
I'm in Seville for work.
I was near the Torre del Oro
and remembered our call.
I saw a boat, and I just called.
When I saw you there,
I thought, "Wow. A miracle."
But you hung up.
You're lying. I don't buy it.
What work? What are you doing here?
I'm showing my photos at this gallery.
I sent you the address.
I've been working on it all year.
You want to come in?
Fuck…
Come. Look.
This grandfather took his six grandkids
to see their sick grandmother.
They traveled almost 50 miles
through the Cambodian jungle.
She held on until they arrived.
After hugging the last one,
she died.
It was my first big trip after graduation.
Those are three elderly trans women
I met in Indiana.
Best friends since childhood.
They'd always lived together
and wanted to grow old in the home.
Every afternoon,
they lip-synced to Gloria Gaynor.
You should've seen it.
They brought the house down.
And that one?
It almost cost me my life.
It was in Norway. The Svalbard islands.
Something started scratching my tent
in the middle of the night.
Making odd noises.
Panting, pushing against the fabric.
My heart rate hit 190.
I didn't sleep. In the morning,
I went out, and there it was.
It had feasted on the food in my backpack.
I left, but it kept following me.
- It knew something.
- What?
I still had chorizo in my backpack.
So the world is yours, huh, Willy Fog?
I'm embarrassed
at how intrusive I've been.
You're right. You have a boyfriend,
He could have been there.
I'm sorry.
This way.
- Hello?
- I have something of yours.
Who's this?
If you want your money back,
go alone to this address,
and don't even think
about calling the cops.
Who is this?
I'll be at the Beata Leonor rose garden
at 9:00 p.m.
In the greenhouse.
If you had a bag with four million
in unmarked 100-euro bills
and called for ransom,
what would you ask for?
- They stole the money?
- Yes. At a party.
- Focus. What would you ask for?
- No fucking idea, Damián.
But it sounds like blackmail.
Who blackmails when they have money?
And how did they get your number?
No idea.
They want to meet at a park at nine.
- Don't go.
- I have to.
It's the only way
to get the four million back.
I'm not going alone
because, yes, it could be dangerous.
Where's Roi?
- Damián, hello.
- Roi, where are you?
An art gallery.
What are you doing there?
- Personal business.
- Personal?
An exhibit. Since we're dealing with art…
In the middle of this,
you go look at paintings?
- Photos.
- Don't bust my balls.
- Get your ass back here.
- Okay.
Fuck.
Hello.
Excuse me.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah.
I'm a friend of Keila's.
I want to talk to her.
Okay. One second, please.
- Keila?
- Yes?
- A friend of yours is here.
- Coming.
Before you say anything,
I came certain of my love for Bruce.
I meant to leave Claudio.
But I realized I was being unfair to him.
He's here in Seville for an exhibit,
not because he's stalking me.
It's the opposite.
You can't imagine his inner world.
His sensitivity, his creativity.
When I saw him, I felt drawn to him
and didn't know why, but now…
Now I understand.
All that sensitivity
made you drop your panties?
You forgave Cameron
for sleeping with someone.
Your girlfriend.
But I "drop my panties"?
If you're worried, don't be.
Given everything, I'll leave Bruce.
Great.
You came to dump Claudio
and realized you need to dump Bruce.
You're unbelievable.
Go. I'll get back on my own.
Okay.
Genoveva?
Shall we sit?
- There's a man inside. See him?
- Yes.
Here's proof I have what you're after.
Take it. It's yours.
What's this about?
If you want your money back,
you'll have to earn it.
Bundle by bundle.
Is this an indecent proposal?
Like Robert Redford's?
Well, obvious differences aside.
I thought it was part of the flirting.
No one leaves four million
mid-conversation and runs.
I thought, "He left it
because he wants to see me again."
Classic move.
So I call you, we arrange to meet
in a mysterious place…
And the offer still stands?
Exactly.
What, you're not interested?
I am. Very much.
But it's not about you bribing me
with your own money,
or that I'm not interested.
I don't think I've ever rejected
such a beautiful woman.
Or ever will
in whatever years I have left.
It's about principle.
I won't betray the man I'm working for.
I sensed you were ethical.
I love it.
But the truth is,
you need your money back,
and I have some very fun ideas.
Want to hear
the first one for half a million?
He's pointing a gun at him. Let's go.
Come on.
The duke gives you his money,
his wife steals it and demands ransom?
Is it a setup, or what?
I've got a bad feeling about this.
I missed the action.
We burst in like Pancho Villa.
Thought they'd kill you.
We should warn Berlin,
get the boat, and leave.
Forget Lady with an Ermine.
Enough, Bruce.
Your drama is clouding your outlook.
Berlin's not here. That makes me boss.
I decide what we do.
Go to sleep. I'll handle it.
We stick to the plan.
He's right. I'm not okay.
Keila met another guy.
It's not the end of the world, right?
Shit. That happens.
It's happened to me, I mean…
And I've done worse than Keila.
- Did I tell you about the twins?
- No.
I hooked up with twins
on a train to Canterbury
while I was with Sheila.
So what did Keila do? Nothing, really.
One sexual encounter.
It sounds boring.
Just once, Roi. Once, man.
She's making out with him now.
What?
She…
She asked me to take her somewhere,
and it was to meet him.
I'm sorry, man.
Come. I've got an idea.
Hold this.
We got something to do.
We were talking business
with the duke and duchess.
The same thing you discussed
in the Niña de los Peines bathroom?
Where were you?
I thought you were asleep.
I went for a walk.
How's your art collection?
Very well.
I'll get a glass of water.
Sir.
Is there a problem?
Did my wife use
the Niña de los Peines bathroom?
Yes. I escorted her.
Did anything happen I should know about?
Was anyone else inside?
It was empty, sir. I checked.
Then why did that woman…
Candela,
suggest my wife was there with a man?
Candela is a friend of hers. From church.
Could be a female conspiracy.
Why didn't you go out with her tonight?
She didn't want me to.
You see?
- See what?
- She's inventing a lover.
Hinting something happened
in that bathroom,
coming home at midnight
with a flower in her hair,
a Mona Lisa smile…
She's punishing me.
Why would she do that?
To get my attention.
I left her alone on her birthday.
She hasn't even worn
the necklace I gave her.
She needs more of me.
But she won't ask directly.
She's too proud.
So she stages this farce.
Thank you, Samuel.
I won't buy more art.
This will be the last piece.
I know I've kept you
in a bubble of art and neurosis.
Now I want you to show me your world.
We could go to Italy.
You always say you want to go back.
Imagine it.
You and me,
the wind on our faces,
heading to Italy.
Yes?
Could you step outside for a moment?
What's the matter?
I know where the money is.
Genoveva has it.
She asked to meet me to return it.
Hey.
Enough leaving me out
with all the whispering.
Tell him whatever he has to say,
he can say it in front of me.
Let's go inside.
Come.
She opened the briefcase and… well…
But I'm one of you, okay?
Tell him. Tell him I'm in the crew.
I'm getting dizzy.
- A bit dramatic, huh?
- A bit.
Come, sit. Here.
Easy.
So can you tell us
why Genoveva has our money?
Apparently, she wants to blackmail me.
Sexually.
Check her out. Spicy.
I didn't know that side of her.
She only has eyes for her husband.
Maybe she's fallen in love.
So what's the problem?
You don't want to give in?
Of course not.
Not out of prudishness. Out of principle.
I won't risk the heist for sex.
Or have sex for money. That'd be insane!
I see flashing neon lights, saying, "No!"
That's a man. I'm with you.
All right.
If we have a moral issue
getting back four million,
the usual guy will solve it.
Who took the red mallet?
Doesn't matter now.
Grab the crowbar. We're leaving.
This is my brother's dream.
- Photocopying bills?
- Something like that.
We've got the four million in photocopies,
but not the hiding place
to make the switch.
She wants the money for erotic blackmail,
so she must have it close to play with it.
It's not at the estate or the palace.
She's got over 12 staff
cleaning under every bed.
If the money's not inside
but can't be outside either, where is it?
In the garage?
She has a black Maserati.
No one's allowed in it.
Not even her butler.
- She's good, huh?
- Yeah.
Pray it's there.
Or you'll have to raid her boudoir.
What are we doing here?
Destroying our past life.
Here.
What's this?
I had a revelation.
Tonight, smashing the glass
in the greenhouse,
I saw myself flying in slow motion.
Like adrenaline and dopamine
woke me from a nightmare.
Try it.
- What nightmare?
- Falling in love.
The nightmare's so fucking good,
you don't know you're in it.
Know why?
Because you think love
is winning the fucking lottery.
But it's a lie.
That's not you.
I used to go skydiving with my friends
and see who waited longest
to pull the cord.
I stole cars, raced down runways
at 200 miles an hour.
And then I fell in love
and discovered fear.
- Fear of what?
- Something happening to me. Or to her.
Or worse. Her leaving.
You end up sitting in salons,
waiting while she gets her hair dyed.
Like a chump.
Because you think that's happiness.
But it's not. It's narcolepsy!
This is for the nights on the sofa,
eating popcorn,
watching other people live on TV.
For the friends you stop seeing.
For the stupid fucking face
I made watching her try on clothes
for an Asian restaurant.
You have to be nuts
to be in a relationship.
But I wasn't.
I was numbed out.
What will you do after the heist?
Go back to Cantabria.
Ride horses naked.
That was amazing.
Those wild horses, galloping.
Why the hell naked?
I've infiltrated the duke's luxury yacht.
The Rosa de los Mares.
How'd you pull that off?
I waited at the port
in front of the yacht.
I found a crew member, Cristina.
- Excuse me.
- I befriended her.
I'm looking to work on a boat.
Well, we're full.
So I asked her for advice.
She was heading to her hotel,
but we started drinking margaritas.
Another one, please.
How'd you get rid of her?
Laxatives.
And I rendered her phone useless.
The boat was leaving.
At 7:00 a.m. I showed up.
- Hello.
I'm a friend of Cristina's. She's sick.
We're sailing to Sardinia
and the Greek islands.
First stop, the Morocco-Algeria border,
to refuel.
All passengers are multimillionaires.
Stay in the background.
See if they transport anything illegal.
If so, what, and photograph it.
We'll use it as leverage
if things go south.
- Okay.
- How many phones did you take?
Three.
Don't save our names.
The duke knows our code names.
Want code names for our code names?
Precisely.
Oh, and…
Be careful on that voyage.
Welcome.
- Everything okay?
- Wonderful.
Come with me.
This will be your space
to create and work.
My favorite place in the palace.
My mothership.
A playground for my senses.
For instance, look at this.
Let's see. Where are you? Here.
A first edition of José de Espronceda.
"The moon on the sea shimmers
and on the sail whispers the wind
which in soft motions raises
waves of silver and blue."
And signed!
Look. Read it.
Read it and pass it on.
Do you like to dance?
You always remember
who first made you dance.
For me, it was…
Elvis!
Look!
The suit he wore for the legendary concert
at the Honolulu International Center Arena
in '73.
And up there, the solar system.
Ten planets. Aren't there eight?
I invented those two.
Télum and Sántalos.
A perfect ten. A magical number.
Isn't it brilliant?
And over here…
You'll like this.
My ice chest.
Excitement whets our appetite.
Yes?
For that, we've got some Alaskan crab,
Swiss chocolate,
and caviar.
And to focus…
frankincense.
I won't bother you anymore.
Genoveva, darling.
Enjoy.
Friends…
Let your seditious ideas flow.
Is no one going to comment
on what we just saw?
This pathetic, tacky,
ridiculous narcissist
reciting Espronceda… God!
What's wrong?
No mics or cameras. All clear.
I'll continue. So affected.
A textbook snob.
Peacocking about Elvis's sequined suit.
Let's unpack the equipment.
We need to check
the palace's remaining security systems.
The cameras have motion sensors.
They only record when someone passes by.
So no one's watching them live.
Exactly. It's a closed circuit.
They only check them
if there's an incident.
How many cameras?
Twenty-four.
If you hack them all,
we'll see the entire palace.
- Can you control the sensors?
- That's it.
We can control when they record.
Careful.
The duke's coming towards you. Don't move.
He's behind you.
- Did he see you looking?
- Don't think so.
I love Ribera.
I'd say even more than Caravaggio.
Interesting.
Do you know Ribera?
He's one of the greats.
He's…
horrifying.
Do you know what Lord Byron
said about him?
He said Ribera
dipped his brush
in the blood of the saints.
Isn't it magnificent?
Do you enjoy Baroque as well?
Yes.
But I prefer the 16th century. El Greco.
I'm delighted to see
you're all so qualified.
I'm extremely moved
by your appreciation of art.
It makes sense you're such geniuses
in your profession.
I'm making a sortie to the garage.
Warn me on the earpiece
if anyone's in my way.
I don't know why he's going there.
Better I don't, right?
Precisely.
Berlin, Samuel's heading down the gallery.
You'll cross paths in seconds.
Careful. Someone's vacuuming.
Now. Quickly.
The parking area is 50 feet ahead.
Next party, leave the money at home.
And when she notices the copies?
A millionaire won't check the bills.
But if she finds out, she'll be thrilled
to know a pro outplayed her.
I'm stepping outside for some air.
Yesterday you hugged me,
and I felt desire in your arms.
I won't deny I was afraid,
but it was the wildest moment
I've had in 20 years.
I know you will deny me a thousand times,
but I trust your instinct more.
It was your instinct that hugged me.
And it's your instinct
I'd like to take on a date.
The next move is yours.
Wear a white shirt,
and you'll hear from me again.
Time to head to the chapel.
Keila, more cameras.
There aren't any inside.
The duke's a devout Catholic.
You need privacy to talk to God.
If he hides dirty money there,
he won't want recordings.
Bruce and I will go.
We'll only take micro cameras.
- And mics?
- Not necessary.
Try not to draw attention.
Okay, the cameras are working.
Why doesn't she want mics?
To talk about their issues.
Their relationship crisis.
Button cams are enough for now.
There's something I need to tell you.
Me too.
Keila, I've been thinking about…
all the women I've kissed
in all the clubs around the world,
the sleepless nights,
the faces I remember
and the names I don't.
I thought it was about fun.
About feeling alive.
But now I know it was all to get to you.
Keila…
You're the best thing in my life.
They're going down.
Entering the chapel.
Path is clear.
Let's do a full sweep.
Smaller than expected.
No visible doors.
There must be an access point.
A tunnel or crypt.
Look, Keila.
You don't need to give up anything.
Meet people. Sleep with people.
With that guy you met.
Call him if you want. Experience that.
I'm in no rush. I make no demands.
Because I already know you're the one.
I want you to experience it all
until you know that I'm the one too.
I didn't know you had this inside you.
I mean, I knew you were a good guy,
but this is something else.
The cameras are fogging up.
What's that? Steam?
- Tears.
- Roi, go down.
Why, sir?
- We'll draw attention if we're all there.
- Go.
Take the radio frequency detectors.
We need to find the entrance
to the money cave.
People spend their lives
looking for one amazing person,
and I found two.
It almost seems unfair.
Not one miracle, but two.
I don't know how to handle this,
because I can't give up either of you.
We have to find the electric spring
that opens the money cave.
Coming through.
Got an electric mechanism.
A mechanical spring opens it.
Like an Indiana Jones movie.
Pure genius.
What's down there?
Do you see anything?
Not much from here, sir.
Roi, give Keila your earpiece
and take a look.
Copy.
Going down.
I'm coming with you.
Bad idea for them to go in without an M16.
Keila, activate the angel's lever again.
Full screen on the patio.
Someone's heading to the chapel.
ETA, five seconds.
Why are you here?
I'm praying.
Chapels bring me peace.
What beautiful flowers.
I bring fresh ones every day
for Don Fernando.
The duke's father.
He was like a father to me.
He rests there.
I lost my mother recently too.
Kidney disease.
In places like this,
I feel like I can talk to her.
Prayer helps me too.
I have something
that may help with your mother.
It means a lot to me.
The Sacred Heart of Jesus.
- May I join you?
- Of course.
You better wear that scapular
every day of your life, you fucking bitch.
Because you'll need divine protection.
You play innocent,
but I remember who you are.
The bitch who gave me this limp.
And I repay insults twice over.
I'll put you in a wheelchair.
In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
- We have to go down.
- No, wait.
Get out of here. Now.
I don't want to see you here again.
You or anyone else.
Out!
Subtitle translation by:
Soledad Etchemendy